# **Harriet Cooper**

I am an experienced project manager with a creative eye and an impressive flair for problem solving! My background is in retail design and events, in which I apply my creative, production and client management skills to get great results.

## **Employment**

### Blacks Visual: Senior Project Manager

July 2017 to June 2019

I am very proud to have been asked back to Blacks where I started my career, to help them take the company into a new chapter of growth. Blacks Visual is an industry leading retail design and production house working from design to installation, creating innovative window displays & in-store environments for exceptional clients. My role ranges from running large scale global projects to bespoke, one off events and exciting big builds.

- I successfully tendered for and onboarded adidas as a new client, being awarded full creative and production responsibility for 8 key city flagship stores throughout Europe. Building a team around their requirements we've delivered some highly successful projects together.
- I have championed and led our move into utilising sustainable materials, helping clients such as COS, Topshop and Reiss in becoming circular.
- Bringing my agency experience back to Blacks saw me implementing numerous new processes to provide efficiencies and collaboration. This included a review of team structure, ways of working, project management tools and getting the team to collaborate and work well together through knowledge shares and creative workshops.
- I have a vast knowledge of materials, production and print and have built up a reliable supplier list. With this I'm able to turn client ideas into working designs, competent briefs and instruct drawings and manufacture for the factory team.
- A favourite project of mine was to create an Indian themed environment within Harrods for Louboutin to launch their CLxSabyasachi collaboration. Christian himself hosted an event in the space that included a handmade rotunda and multiple adapted spaces within the worldfamous department store.

### **Intermarketing Agency: Senior Account Manager**

June 2016 to June 2017

Intermarketing is a global creative agency with digital, motion, creative, 3D, retail, insight and experiential functions. I led the Reebok account internally and externally implementing and advising on their European marketing strategy online and in the retail environment.

- I was brought into the retail team to look after the new Reebok opportunity, I built a successful client relationship and increased the profitability of the account tenfold in 6 months. I also secured further business across training and fashion, resulting in doubling the team.
- My team implemented our creative concepts and events across JD Sports, ASOS, Sports Direct, LSS, Lillywhites, Sweatshop, etc and handled all production, planning and retailer relationships for the client and brands.
- We created global shopper marketing guidelines and toolkits for Reebok to roll out to markets and retailers, which aligned all consumer instore, online and OOH creative.
- I worked across a number of confidential brand developments, such as new partnerships with Gigi Hadid, ensuring we launched into the markets cohesively for the consumer.
- I was responsible for all client commercials and looked after forecasting, budgeting and managing any pipeline opportunities to achieve targets.

## We are Vista: Creative Services Project Manager

### March 2015 to June 2016

Vista is a full-service events and creative agency with in-house film, digital, design, production, content and communication teams. I oversaw and led the project management and event styling.

- My team delivered the highly successful MINI Clubman roadshow after presenting and winning the work at competitive pitch. I led the design and creation of a stylised masculine environment to promote the MINI at 9 amazing venues across the UK over 3 weeks. We delivered catering, experiences, promotion and presentations and had great feedback from the client; www.citmagazine.com/article/1370779/mini-appointsvista-ahead-clubman-launch.
- I won new clients such as D&D bars Leeds, creating bespoke pop up bars, Christmas schemes and events and delivered experiential marketing projects for NatWest, including animated roadshow window displays.
- I was responsible for managing costs and suppliers, monitoring progress and time spent on projects, while keeping my clients up to date with regular meetings, de-briefs and critical paths.

## **Blacks Visual Merchandising Ltd: Project Manager**

May 2010 to March 2015

Starting my creative career at Blacks provided me with great knowledge of the creative and manufacture process, covering joinery, cnc, spray effects, fabrication, print and logistics. Having all production in house taught me how to take a client's idea and make it happen, nothing is impossible!

- I was responsible for managing Blacks' largest client Debenhams, leading the team who implemented the in-store bespoke branding for 172 stores.
- I delivered Marc Bollands 'New M & S' concept, initially at their Olympic flagship store, rolling out further following its success.
- I tendered for, costed and managed window design, manufacture and installation for brands such as Mulberry, Asprey, Polo Ralph Lauren, Topshop, New Look and Miss Selfridge with all my projects being profitable and on schedule.
- I managed a team of on-site installers and surveyors and was the site/installation manager when required.

## Freedom Group: Project Manager

September 2007 to May 2010

At Freedom I was responsible for the operational management of a £5million security project. The role saw me managing stakeholders, suppliers, budgets and schedules to make sure the project came in under budget and met government regulations.

#### Education

### **Huddersfield University**

2004 to 2007

BA (Hons) Creative Imaging: Graphic Design and Business Management - 2:1 Honours

## **Huddersfield Technical College**

2002 to 2004

BTEC National Diploma (Marketing) - Graphic Design and Art A Level

**Castle Hall School** 1997 to 2002

GCSE: 13 A-C Including Maths and English

## Other things you may need to know...

Full clean driving licence

PC Literate: Microsoft Office, Excel Wiz (It's always important to have one on hand in the office!)

#### **Interests**

I enjoy spending time with friends, watching live music and going to festivals. I'm really into running, mostly to counteract my love of real ale, and love to read when I'm not researching my next adventure. I'm currently on a mission to 'complete' Europe.